Guide to the Miscellaneous Scripts Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Miscellaneous Scripts Collection
1938-2002
1978-1986
DRA 38
Yale University Arts Library
3.75
(3 boxes)
This collection consists of scripts written for the stage, screen, and television. It includes scripts from the "American Playhouse" PBS television series and the Federal Theatre Project.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The individual scripts were housed in the former Drama Library until their transfer to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library in 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of scripts written for the stage, screen, and television. It includes scripts from the "American Playhouse" PBS television series and the Federal Theatre Project.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Plays. II. Screenplays. III. Teleplays.
Arranged alphabetically by title within each series or subseries. More detailed inventory of contents available in repository.
Drama; Scripts (documents)
- Plays, Series I
  - Various scripts for plays, 1976-2000 undated; 11 (Box 1)
  - Federal Theatre Project, 1938 undated; 5 (Box 1)
- Screenplays, Series II
  - Various scripts for screenplays, 1973-1986 undated; 10 items (Box 1)
  - Various scripts for screenplays, 1978-1991 undated; 7 items (Box 2)
- Teleplays, Series III
  - Various scripts for teleplays, 1954-2002 undated; 17 items (Box 2)
  - Various scripts for teleplays, 1986-2001 undated; 5 items (Box 3)
  - American Playhouse Scripts, 1970-1984 undated; 15 (Box 3)